Guide to the Millard Walter Hastay Papers 1937-1981
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Millard Walter Hastay Papers
1937-1981
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 592
Hastay, Millard Walter, 1916-
9 containers. 12 linear feet of shelf space.
Correspondence, research notes and teaching materials. Some materials concern research on expectations and business cycles.
Millard Hastay was born in Montana, Sep. 8, 1916. He graduated from high school at Portland, Oregon, in 1934. He completed undergraduate education at Reed College in 1941. His graduate education was at Stanford University and at Columbia University. He received the Ph.D. degree from Columbia in 1958. From 1946 to 1958 he worked as an economics researcher with the National Bureau of Economic Research in New York. He also taught economics at the City College of New York from 1954 to 1958. In 1958 Hastay began employment at Washington State University. There he specialized in economic theory, econometrics, statistics and related subjects. He retired in 1981.
The papers of Millard Hastay consist of research materials and drafts associated with research projects, both at the National Bureau of Economic Research and at Washington State University, as well as correspondence, memoranda, and a variety of documents concerning economics classes and graduate education at Washington State University. The arrangement is that in use by Hastay at the time the papers were transferred to the Libraries.
This arrangement groups the papers into six series: 1) Columbia River water economics research projects, 2) Instruction and teaching, 3) National Bureau of Economic Research, 4) Graduate student projects; miscellaneous projects, 5) Professional and university faculty concerns, 6) Oversize and legal size materials.
This collection is open for research use.
Papers of Millard W. Hastay, Professor of Economics at Washington State University, were donated to the Washington State University Libraries by Mr. Hastay in l981 (Accession No. MS81-36).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Hastay, Millard Walter, 1916- --Archives
Washington State University--Faculty -- Archives; National Bureau of Economic Research
Economics -- Study and teaching--Washington (State)--Pullman
Science; Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
Economics teachers -- 20th century--Washington (State)--Pullman--Archives
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Series 1. Columbia River Water Research
  - A Study of Certain Aspects of the Water Resources of the State of Washington, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Study of Water Resources in Washington, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advisory Committee on Weather Control, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - An Initial Study of the Water Resources of the State of Washington, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Analysis Using Orthogonal Polynomials and Autocorrelation, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Columbia Basin Inter-agency Committee Water Management Subcommittee, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Columbia River as a Resource, Present and Future Values of Columbia River Waters, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Columbia River Basin Streamflow, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Columbia River Valuations, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Folder numbers not used (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
  - Economic Models, Value of the Columbia River, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Equilibrium System, Water Coefficient, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Evaluation of the Columbia River as a Resource, Production Studies, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Hydroelectric Power Systems, Research, 1964-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Manufacturing Data, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Marginal Pollution Studies, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Measurement of Technological Progress, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Meetings and Consultation, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Outline of Report on Washington Projections, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Participant Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Precipitation and Watershed Studies, 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Productivity, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Productivity and Relative Charts, Includes Forestry, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Projection Syllabus and Miscellaneous Notes, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Revision of Paper on Snake River Diversion, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Specialty Conference, Pullman, Diversion of Columbia Waters, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Statistical Evaluation of Cloud-Seeding Critique, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Statistical Evaluation of Effects of Cloud Seeding, Runoff of Skagit River Watershed, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Folder number not used (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - University Council on Water Resources, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Washington State Interindustry Projections, Appendices, 1960-2065 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Washington Water Research Center, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Washington Water Research Center Budget, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Water Resource Research, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Weather Modification Study, Concrete, undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Working Notes, 1962-1968 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Series 2. Instruction and teaching
  - Series 2.1. Courses in Economics--Graduate
    - Bibliographies, 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Course Outlines, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Course Proposals, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Economics 340: Public Finance, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Economics 401: Advanced Economic Theory, Notes, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Economics 410: Mathematical Economics, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Economics 411: Econometrics, 1964-1978 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Economics 411: Econometrics, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Economics 411: Econometrics, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Economics 411: Econometrics, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Economics 411: Econometrics, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Economics 501: Systematic Microeconomics, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Economics 501: Systematic Microeconomics, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Economics 501: Systematic Microeconomics, 1976-1979 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Economics 502: Macroeconomic Analysis, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Economics 502: Macroeconomic Analysis, 1963-1967 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Economics 503: Methodology in Economics, 1964-1970 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Economics 503: Methodology in Economics, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Economics 512: Seminar Evaluations, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Economics 520: Monetary Theory and Policy, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Economics Courses, 1948-1976 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Grad File, Spring, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Graduate Programs, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Oral Preliminaries, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Ph.D Core Examinations, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Ph.D Examinations, Economics, 1942-1951 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Ph.D Preliminary Examination, Econometrics, 1962-1980 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Ph.D Preliminary Examinations, 1958-1969 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Ph.D Preliminary Examinations Theory, 1960-1976 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Theses, 1965-197? (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Theses and Requirements, 1962-1977 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Series 2.2. Courses in Economics, Undergraduate
    - Economics 9, Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Economics 21, Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Economics 301: Intermediate Economic Theory, 1959-1981 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Economics 301: Theory of the Firm and Market Policy, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Economics 301: Theory of the Firm and Market Policy, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - Economics 301: Theory of the Firm and Market Policy, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - Economics 301: Theory of the Firm and Market Policy, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 76)
    - Economics 301: Managerial Version, 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - Economics 320: Money and Banking, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - Economics 511: Econometrics, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - Economics Exams, 1958-1964 (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - Economics Grade Books, 1957-1977 (Box 5, Folder 81)
- Series 3. National Bureau of Economic Research
  - Abramovitz, Moe: Conversations with, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - Analysis of Businessmen's Expectations, 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Annual Report Summaries, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Basic Diffusion Data, Manufacturers' Inventories, Weighted Balances and Diffusion, 1948-1956 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Bureau of Labor Statistics Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Business Expectations Study, 1954-1962 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Classification Problem, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Comments on Capital-Output Ratios and Miscellaneous Materials, undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Conferences, 1952-1963 (Box 5, Folder 89.1)
  - Cyclical Behavior of Industrial Equipment and Investment, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 89.2)
  - Data Sheets, 1946-1953 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Data Sheets Diffusion, 1949-1957 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Diffusion Index, Status of Indicators, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Dun and Bradstreet Survey, 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Dun and Bradstreet Weights and Diffusion Indexes, 1953-54 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Dun's Expectation Index, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Durable Goods Manufactures, 1949-1960 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Electronic Applications, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Evaluations of Papers, 1946-1956 (Box 6, Folder 98)
  - Experiments, Iterations, 1946-1953 (Box 6, Folder 99)
  - Federal Reserve Board Correspondence, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 100)
  - Federal Reserve Board Task Committee on General Business Expectations, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 101)
  - Forecasting Unemployment by Leading Series, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 102)
  - Hand-Written Models, undated (Box 6, Folder 103)
  - Indicator Theory, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 104)
  - Long-Cycle Calculations, undated (Box 6, Folder 105)
  - Long-Cycle Experiments, undated (Box 6, Folder 106)
  - Long-Cycle Study, Dr. Hastay and Milton Friedman, undated (Box 6, Folder 107)
  - Long Cycles, late Nineteenth Century, early Twentieth Century, undated (Box 6, Folder 108)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 6, Folder 109)
  - Mitchell, Wesley C.: Hastay's Correspondence, 1946-1948. (Box 6, Folder 110)
  - Mitchell, Wesley C.: Supplementary Bibliography, 1949-1953 (Box 6, Folder 111)
  - Models: First-Stage Regression, 1947-1957 (Box 6, Folder 112)
  - Models: Least Squares and Reduced Form, 1953-1957 (Box 6, Folder 113)
  - Models: Second-Stage Regression, 1954-1957 (Box 6, Folder 114)
  - Modigliani, Franco, to Millard Hastay, and Data, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 115)
  - Monetary Factors in Business Cycles, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 116)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1937-1951 (Box 6, Folder 117)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research Advisory Services, Millard Hastay to Dr. Lawrence Klein, February 6, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 118)
  - Notes on Seasonals, 1940-1949 (Box 6, Folder 119)
  - Notes on Technique, undated (Box 6, Folder 120)
  - Outline of Models, 1949-1966 (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Papers on Seasonal Variations, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 122)
  - Preliminary Report on Economic Projections For Selected Geographic Areas--1929-2020, Vol. I, United States Water Resources Council, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Preliminary Report On Economic Projections for Selected Geographic Areas--1929-2020, Vol. I, United States Water Resources Council, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Public Capital Outlays, 1945-1950 (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Realized Diffusion Models, U1--Estimates of Y and Contributing Components, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Regression, 1-108; Estimates of Y, undated (Box 6, Folder 127)
  - Robert Ferber's Review of Dun and Bradstreet Paper, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 128)
  - Spatial Aspects of Economic Change, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 129)
  - Seminar Talk on Research in Businessmen's Expectations, undated (Box 6, Folder 130)
  - Seventeenth European Meeting of the Econometric Society, Kiel, Germany (Box 6, Folder 131)
  - Survey of Businessmen's Expectations, Dun and Bradstreet, 1954-1966 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - Sweden, Basic Data, 1949-1961 (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - Time--Series Data Sheet, 1946-1965 (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - Wallis, W. Allen, Rough and Ready Statistical Tests, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 135)
- Series 4. Graduate Student and Miscellaneous Projects
  - Abu-Bakr, Ahmed, Ph.D. Thesis, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 136)
  - Administrative Procedures, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 137)
  - Consumption Expenditures, Richard Stillson, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 137.1)
  - Dissertation Proposals, 1954-1970 (Box 7, Folder 138)
  - Exam for Junior Statistician, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 139)
  - Extension for Gary A. Lynch, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 140)
  - Faculty-Student Coordinating Committee, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 141)
  - Grohs, Roy, Ph.D. Thesis, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 142)
  - Hodgson, Frank to Millard C. Hastay, Projected Washington Interindustry Structure, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 143)
  - Letters of Inquiry, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 144)
  - Lewis, Edward E., A Conspectus of Business Cycle Problems, undated (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Math Sciences Council, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Ryder, David Owen, Ph.D. Thesis Proposal, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Statistics Curriculum in the Age of Computers; Discussions of Mr. Lebergott's and Dr. Hoagland's Papers; and: Francis J. Kottke (Box 7, Folder 147.1)
  - Tonkovitch, Franz, Thesis, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 148)
  - Walsh, Vivian C.: Ad Hoc Committee to Evaluate his Publications, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 149)
- Series 5. Professional and Faculty Concerns
  - Administrative Notices and Graduate Procedures, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Bibliographic, 1947-1980 (Box 7, Folder 151)
  - Conference on Expectations, Uncertainty, and Business Behavior, 1954-1956 (Box 7, Folder 152)
  - Cooperation with Agriculture-Economics, 1973-1978 (Box 7, Folder 153)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1971-1980 (Box 7, Folder 154)
  - Department Rules and Policies, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 155)
  - Funded Research, 1973-1975 (Box 7, Folder 156)
  - Graduate Faculty Candidacies, 1971-1980 (Box 7, Folder 157)
  - Hastay, Millard, Correspondence Personal and Professional, 1949-1965 (Box 7, Folder 158)
  - Hastay, Millard, Correspondence Personal and Professional (Box 7, Folder 159)
  - Hastay, Millard, Publications and Correspondence, 1952-1960 (Box 8, Folder 160)
  - Letters of Reference, 1959-1975 (Box 8, Folder 161)
  - Letters of Reference, 1960-1968 (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Letters of Reference, 1964-1970 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Letters of Reference, 1972-1981 (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Library Procedure, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Managerial Economics Committee, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 166)
  - Publication Lists, 1962-1971 (Box 8, Folder 167)
  - Research Grants, 1959-1969 (Box 8, Folder 168)
  - Research Topics, 1962-1978 (Box 8, Folder 169)
  - Resumes, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 170)
  - Resumes, Statistical, 1962-1971 (Box 8, Folder 171)
  - Staff Vitae, undated (Box 8, Folder 172)
  - Tenure, 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 173)
  - Visiting Scholars, Procedures and Correspondence, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 174)
- Series 6. Legal size, oversize (Misc. Economics Projects)
  - California and Washington Interindustry Structure, based on Moore-Peterson, 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 175)
  - Productivity Studies, undated (Box 9, Folder 176)
  - The Cyclical Behavior of Investment, undated (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Washington Interindustry Studies, Projections, 1960-2065 and: Small Business Administration Surveys (Box 9, Folder 178)
  - Washington State Projections: Population, Labor Force, Employment, 1945-1976 (Box 9, Folder 179)